hackerearth.com 2019-05-08

# Privacy Policy | HackerEarth

##### Updated: 25th May, 2018

HackerEarth Inc. is committed to protecting your privacy and ensuring that you have a positive experience on our website and while using our products and services (collectively, "Products"). This  policy covers  the HackerEarth website hackerearth.com and all the subdomains under hackerearth.com. Please refer to the following link to read our  terms of service . 

This policy outlines our handling practices and how we collect and use the Personal Data you provide during your interactions with us. In this Privacy Policy, ‘Personal Data’ means any information that can be used to individually identify a person and may include, but is not limited to, name, email address, postal or other physical addresses, title, and other personally identifiable information.

If you reside in the European Union (“EU”), United Kingdom, Lichtenstein, Norway, Iceland, or Switzerland, you may have additional rights with respect to your Personal Data, as further outlined below. These rights may include rights under the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), if you are a resident of the EU, United Kingdom, Lichtenstein, Norway, or Iceland.

HackerEarth Inc. will be the controller of the Personal Data that is provided, collected and/or processed pursuant to this Privacy Policy, except where otherwise expressly stated. If you have any questions about whether any of foregoing applies to you, please contact us using the information set forth in the ‘Contact Us’ section below.

This policy may be updated from time-to-time for reasons such as operational practices or regulatory changes, so we recommend that you review our Privacy Policy when returning to our website after a gap.

### About GDPR

General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is designed to give EU citizens more control over their data. It aims to use an all-encompassing privacy and security law to safeguard personal data. Irrespective of their location, GDPR applies to all the relevant controllers or processors who deal with the personal data of EU citizens.

For more information, see:

### Collecting your Personal Data

We collect the following Personal Data about you when you use or otherwise interact with our Products:

  * Name (First name/last name/full name)
  * Title
  * Email ID (both personal and professional)

Since HackerEarth acts as a Data Processor, the Data Controller may choose to collect some of the following additional details.

  * Profile/display picture
  * Country, state, postcode or city of residence
  * Login name, screen name, nickname, or handle
  * Telephone number (Home/work/mobile telephone number)
  * Postal or other physical address
  * Date of birth
  * Gender
  * Name(s) of the school/university (including grades and graduation year)
  * Name(s) of the workplace
  * Job position/designation (including salary)
  * Resume/CV
  * Information related to social profiles, such as  Facebook, Google, GitHub etc.
  * IP addresses and other information collected passively, as further detailed in the  “Passive Collection” section  below

We collect and/or process your Personal Data as a part of the following activities related to our Products:

  * Account registration
  * Use of certain Product features
  * Creating or taking tests
  * Generating reports based on information collected from use of our Products
  * Requesting service and support for our Products and providing such support
  * Registering for an event (challenge, hackathon, etc)
  * Participating in an online survey
  * Participating in discussion groups or forums
  * Registering for newsletter subscriptions
  * Customizing the content you see as per relevance

### Processing your Personal Data

We will use your Personal Data only in accordance with our Privacy Policy. If you do not wish us to continue using your Personal Data in this manner, you can request that your account be deactivated from your profile  settings .

We will only process your Personal Data if we have a lawful basis for doing so, which includes but is not limited to the following: consent, contractual necessity (i.e. processing that is necessary for the performance of a contract with you, such as your user agreement with us that allows us to provide you with the Products) and our legitimate interests or the legitimate interest of others (e.g. our users) such as:

  * Personalizing, improving or operating our Products and business
  * Understanding your needs and interests
  * Fulfilling requests you make related to the Products
  * Providing you with relevant information
  * Complying with our legal obligations, resolving disputes with users, enforcing our agreements
  * Protecting, investigating and deterring against fraudulent, harmful, unauthorized or illegal activity

We process Personal Data for purposes such as:

  * Providing reports based on information collected from use of our Products
  * Keeping you up-to-date about latest Product announcements, software updates, software upgrades, system enhancements, special offers, and other information
  * Providing support and assistance for our Products
  * Providing the ability to create personal profile 
  * Providing the ability to contact you, if required
  * Providing customer feedback and support
  * Providing and administering opt-in events or other marketing or promotional activities on HackerEarth
  * Being able to conduct questionnaires and surveys in order to provide you with better products and services
  * Supporting recruitment inquiries
  * Personalizing marketing communication and website content based on your preferences, such as in response to your request for specific information on products and services that may be of interest to you
  * Meeting contract or legal obligations

### Invites

If you choose to use our invite service to tell a friend about our products, you represent that you have your friend’s consent to give us their name and email ID. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting them to visit our website. Unless otherwise authorized by your friend, we will only use your friend’s name and email address for the purposes of sending them this one-time email and maintaining an activity log of our referral program.

### Choice

You can choose whether to provide Personal Data to HackerEarth but note that you may  not  be able to access certain options, offers, and services if they require Personal Data that you have not provided. You can sign-up, and therefore consent, to receive email or newsletter communication from us. If you would like to discontinue receiving  this  communication, you can update your preferences by using the ‘Unsubscribe’ link  at the end of  such emails or by contacting us through email on  [contact@hackerearth.com](mailto:contact@hackerearth.com)  or  [support@hackerearth.com](mailto:support@hackerearth.com) .

### Data subjects rights

You have certain rights with respect to your Personal Data as  mentioned  below. Please note that in some circumstances, we may not be able to fully comply with your requests or we may ask you to provide us with additional information in connection with your request, which may be Personal Data, for example, if we need to verify your identity or the nature of your request. In such situations, however, we will still respond to let you know our decision.

To make any of the following requests, contact us using through email on  [contact@hackerearth.com](mailto:contact@hackerearth.com)  or  [support@hackerearth.com](mailto:support@hackerearth.com) .

  * Access : You can request more information about the Personal Data we hold about you. You can also request a copy of the Personal Data.
  * Rectification : If you believe that any Personal Data we are holding about you is incorrect or incomplete, you can request that we correct or supplement such data. You can also correct some of this information directly through your user profile or profile/account  settings  after logging into HackerEarth. Please contact us as soon as possible upon noticing any inaccurac ies  or incompleteness.
  * Objection : You can contact us to let us know that you object to the collection or use of your Personal Data for certain purposes.
  * Deleting data : You can request that we delete some or all of your Personal Data from our systems. While this will be done immediately, residual data may be saved in certain logs and this will be purged within a year after deleting your data. Once your data is deleted, you will no longer have an account with HackerEarth.
  * Processing r estriction s : You can always request  us to deactivate  your HackerEarth account to restrict further processing of your Personal Data.
  * Portability : You have the right to ask for a copy of your Personal Data in a machine-readable format. 
  * Withdrawal of  c onsent : If we are processing your Personal Data based on your consent (as indicated at the time of collection of such data), you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. Please note, however, that if you exercise this right, you may have to then provide express consent on a case-by-case basis for the use or disclosure of certain of your Personal Data, if such use or disclosure is necessary to enable you to utilize some or all of our Products.
  * Right to  f ile  a c> omplaint : You have the right to lodge a complaint about HackerEarth’s practices with respect to your Personal Data with the supervisory authority of your country or EU Member State.

### Data retention

Your data is retained with HackerEarth as long as you have a HackerEarth account.

You can request that we delete some or all of your Personal Data from our systems. While this will be done immediately, residual data may be saved in certain logs and this will be purged within a year after deleting your data. 

Once your data is deleted, you will no longer have an account with HackerEarth.

### >Passive collection

HackerEarth automatically collect s  some information about you when you use our Products, using methods such as cookies and tracking technologies (further described below). Information automatically collected includes  cookies,   page - view activity, geolocation data,  Internet  P rotocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet  S ervice  P rovider (ISP), referring/exit pages, files viewed on our site (e.g., HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, date /time stamp, and/or clickstream data to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the website and/or Products . Such data does not have an expiry date and we don't delete this data. It is saved with us in log form or on on tools such as Google Analytics, LinkedIn Insights, Facebook Audience Insights etc.

Additionally , when you use some of our Products, network information such as Product - usage information  is transmitted back to us . This information is transmitted back to us so  that  we can determine how users are interacting with our Products . This helps us in  improving our Products  and correct ing  any problems that may occur .

### Cookies and tracking technologies

HackerEarth uses cookies or similar technologies to analyze trends, administer its website, track users’ movements around the website, and gather information about our user base, such as  location information based on IP addresses . 

Users can control the use of cookies in the browsers that they use. Your browser may offer you a ‘Do Not Track’ option, which allows you to signal to operators of websites and web applications and services (including behavioral advertising services) that you do not want such operators to track your online activities and across different websites. 

Our Products  do not support  ‘Do Not Track’ requests at this time, which means that we will collect information about your online activity both while you are using the Products and after you leave our properties.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but provide controls that allow you to block or delete them. For example, in most modern browsers, you can block or delete cookies by clicking  Settings>Privacy>Cookies . Instructions for blocking or deleting cookies in other browsers may be available in a browser's privacy or help documentation. 

To read more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit  [www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/&sa=D&ust=1527251511070000) .

Certain features of HackerEarth Products depend on cookies and plugins.  Please be aware that if you choose to block cookies and plugins, you may not be able to sign in or use those features . Preferences that are dependent on cookies may be lost. If you choose to delete cookies, settings and preferences controlled by those cookies, including advertising preferences, will be deleted and may need to be recreated.

HackerEarth (“Company”, “we”,“our”, or “us”) collects information related to visitors and machines. Such information includes cookies, IP addresses, pageview activities, and geolocation data.The details of user activities on the HackerEarth’s website such as number of visits, time spent on the our website, and pages clicked are also collected.

The types of cookies used by us and their purpose are as follows:

Cookie

| 

Purpose

| 

Process  
  
---|---|---  
  
Advertising cookies

| 

Interest-based advertising

| 

We collect data about your online activity on our website and based on your interests, we show advertisements relevant to you.   
  
Universal Analytics

| 

Analytics

| 

We collect data pertaining to your visits, activities on our website and utilize them to get reports on the performance of our pages. This is done by third-party analytics providers. The purpose of this is to improve user experience on our website and products.  
  
Media cookies

| 

Social media

| 

Our website has social media cookies that relay your identifier information to your media account when logged in, in order to show relevant advertisements to you based on your activities on our website. The social media cookies are used for Facebook, LinkedIn, YouTube, and Twitter. If you no longer want to have these cookies enabled, you can change the settings from your device browser by logging into your social media account and changing the privacy settings.  
  
### Ad cookies

 (Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter)

__cfduid  
  
---  
  
bcookie  
  
personalization_id  
  
tfw_exp  
  
### Analytics cookies

  used  (Google Analytics and Hubspot)

__hssc  
  
---  
  
__hssrc  
  
__hstc  
  
_ga  
  
_gid  
  
hubspotutk  
  
Other personal identifiable information that is collected may be highlighted in other sections of this Privacy Policy or by a dedicated explanation when the data collection happens. Personal data may be freely provided by visitors or collected automatically while using any other platforms related to HackerEarth.

### Interest-based advertisements

We use cookies to gather information about your activities on our website in order to provide you advertising based on your browsing activity and interest.  We also partner with third parties to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Some of our third party partners use technologies such as cookies and other technologies to gather information about your activities on this website, our affiliates’ websites, and unaffiliated websites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests.  

### Mobile application

When you download and use our Products, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier (or ”UDID“). We send you push notifications from time-to-time in order to update you about any events or promotions that we may be running. If you no longer wish to receive these types of communication, you can turn these off from your device. To ensure you receive proper notifications, we will need to collect certain information about your device such as operating system and user identification information.

### Geolocation

We collect information about where you are located when you are using our Products. We use this information for purposes such as optimizing your connection to our data center and suggesting customizations to your experience with our Products (e.g. your language preference, relevant events, challenges, hackathons, etc.). We share this information with parties such as our data center provider. If you do not wish to allow us to share your information in this manner, please opt-out by contacting us at  [support@hackerearth.com](mailto:support@hackerearth.com) .

Certain features of HackerEarth products depend on geolocation. Please be aware that your experience on the website may not be optimal if you choose to block your geolocation identity. Y ou may not be able to sign in or use those features, and preferences that are dependent on geolocation may be lost. 

### Sharing your Personal Data

We do not share, rent, or sell your Personal Data to third parties unless you have granted us explicit permission to do so.

We share Personal Data within HackerEarth, its affiliated companies, and with third-party service providers for purposes of data processing or storage.

We also share Personal Data with business partners, service vendors and/or authorized third-party agents or contractors in order to provide requested Products or transactions, including but not limited to, hosting websites, hosting event and seminar registration and providing customer support. We provide the Personal Data to these third parties in order to complete/utilize the requested Product or transaction.

In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the transferred business assets. Moreover, if we, or substantially all of our assets, were acquired, or if we go out of business or enter bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of us or our assets may continue to use your Personal Data as set forth in this policy. As required by law, we may respond to subpoenas, court orders, or similar legal process by disclosing your Personal Data and other related information, if necessary. We also may use Personal Data and other related information to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims. 

We collect and possibly share Personal Data and any other additional information available to us in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of HackerEarth's terms of service, or as otherwise required by law. 

While navigating HackerEarth's website or Products, you may be directed to content or functionality that is hosted by a third-party. When information is collected on behalf of HackerEarth exclusively, HackerEarth’s Privacy Policy will be referenced and will govern how your information is used. For other, non-HackerEarth sites or services, the site/service owner's privacy policy will be referenced. You should review such third party’s privacy and security policies prior to use.

### Security of your Personal Data

HackerEarth is committed to protecting the Personal Data you share with us. We utilize a combination of industry-standard security technologies, procedures, and organizational measures to help protect your Personal Data from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure.

We recommend that you take every precaution in protecting your Personal Data when you are on the Internet. For example, change your passwords often, use a combination of letters and numbers when creating passwords, and make sure you use a secure browser. If you have any questions about the security of your Personal Data, you can contact us at  support@hackerearth.com .

### Linked websites and third party services

Our websites and services may provide links to other third-party websites and services which are outside our control and not covered by this policy. We encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on these (and all) sites you visit or services you use.

### Forums/Newsgroups

If you participate in a HackerEarth discussion forum or message, you should be aware that the information you provide there will be made broadly available to others (potentially inside or outside HackerEarth) who have access to that discussion forum or message. Also, please recognize that individual forums and messages may have additional rules and conditions. Each participant's opinion on a forum or chat room is his or her own and should not be considered as reflecting the opinion of HackerEarth.

### Contact us

HackerEarth Inc.

2600 El Camino Real, Suite 403

Palo Alto, California, 94306
